José Martins

Email: josepedromartins.dev@gmail.com, Phone: +351 969-559-096, Portfolio: josepedro-martins.github.io

SUMMARY

I am a Gameplay Programmer, proficient in using C# and C++. I have practice working with Unreal Engine and Unity, having developed single and multiplayer projects, and creating engaging experiences in games.

Accustomed to working with close deadlines and team-based environment, having to manage and assist with project organization.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Proficiency using C#, C++, and other OOP languages.
- Experienced working with WordPress, HTML and CSS.
- Experienced working with Unreal Engine and Unity.
- 3+ Years of experience working with video games.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Unity Developer Intern, Volt Games

March 2023 – June 2023

- Worked on MetaStar Strikers, a Web3 football game, performing tasks related to bug fixing and UI programming.
- Worked on the prototype of MetaStar Companion, an idle training game, performing tasks related to AI programming, gameplay programming and game polishing.
- Collaborated daily with a team of 7 programmers.

Game Programmer, Freelance

November 2019 – September 2023

- Developed different genres of video games, using Unreal Engine and Unity.
- Accustomed to team work and task management.
- Familiarized to problem-solving.

Game Programmer, Cranky Bunch Studios

February 2022 – September 2022

- Developed Amissio Insaniae, using Unreal Engine.
- Responsible for all Programming tasks, UI and Sound.

Game Developer, Snake Marmalade Studios

November 2020 – January 2021

- Developed Marmalade Thief, using GB Studio.
- Responsible for Programming and Game Design tasks.
- Wrote and published the game on itch.io platform.

Part-Time Front-End Developer, SM Cosmetology

July 2019 – Present Day

- Responsible for front-end website layout, and plugin management.
- In charge of dealing with website maintenance.

Front-End Developer Intern, Fullback | Sports Tech & Sports Management Consulting November 2019 – May 2020

- Developed the website from scratch, installing plugins in WordPress, and configuring the overall look and layout.
- Received ratings of excellence for every performance and task I have developed.
- Dealt with the website response and behavior.

Full Stack Developer Intern, CodeBehind Tech

June 2018 – August 2018

- Dealt with back-end website related issues.
- Management over the front-end content of the website.
- Day-to-day team management over the tasks provided.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN GAMES AND MULTIMEDIA – INSTITUTO POLITÉCNICO DE LEIRIA – PORTUGAL

- Particularized in programming with C# and C++.
- Specialized in Unreal Engine and Unity.
- Knowledgeable of Multiplayer Networking, and Artificial Intelligence.
- Writing documentation for Game Design, Marketing and Business.

OTHER ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Experience with managing small game development teams with crucial time management.
- Leader of a small team while working as an intern for CodeBehind Tech.
- Second Best Game Design Digital Prototype Marmalade Thief was elected as the Second Best Digital Prototype for a Game Design school project.
- Created my own 2D Custom Game Engine.